# **NADUN DE SILVA**

### **Senior Software Engineer**

• Auckland, New Zealand
• https://linkedin.com/in/nadundesilva

https://nadundesilva.github.iohttps://github.com/nadundesilva

# Summary

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in cloud-native application development and data analytics in Kubernetes and other Cloud Infrastructure. Background in architecture, user experience (UX), development, and deployment of cloud-native applications in production environments. Experience in owning the technical direction of a product area and leading a team of engineers.

# **Experience**

### Senior Software Engineer

**Orion Health** 

- iii November 2022 to Present
- Auckland, New Zealand
- Led the AWS deployment of Indexity, including threat modeling, privacy assessments, observability, and disaster recovery.
- Designed and implemented the CI/CD pipelines and processes for deploying released product artifacts on AWS.
- Improved patient search accuracy of Phone number-based search using Apache Lucene-based indexes.
- Developed the Terraform code for deploying self-hosted GitLab runners on Google Cloud, reducing the development costs by more than 50%.

#### Associate Technical Lead

WSO2

- iii June 2021 to November 2022
- Colombo, Sri Lanka
- Achieved the Sustained Outstanding Contribution Award for the third consecutive year currently awarded only for the top 5% of the employees in the company.
- Led another engineer in developing the minimum viable features for Choreo online editor's resource scheduling, within 1.5 months, using Kubernetes and GoLang.
- Eliminated bottlenecks reducing the startup time of the Kubernetes resources of the Choreo Editors by 80% and increasing the overall user experience.
- Reduced the MsSQL DB utilization by 60%, by introducing a Redis cache and randomization of cache expiry times, increasing the number of users the system can handle.
- Completed 95% of the targets and sprint milestones on time, by prioritization of tasks and fostering a good working environment.

### Senior Software Engineer

WSO<sub>2</sub>

**i** July 2019 to June 2021

- Oclombo, Sri Lanka
- Spearheaded the implementation of the foundation for Choreo observability within 3 months, with a team of 2 other engineers, creating the backbone of Choreo observability.
- Decreased the cost by 90% for the company, by architecting the Choreo observability storages with data archival into a Data Lake for Machine Learning (ML) use cases.
- Improved debugging experience for users, by revamping the observability instrumentation at Ballerina compiler level, within 1 month, to map the observability data to the source code.
- Minimized the number of bugs Choreo Observability area by implementing proper code reviewing, testing and deployment practices in a team of 6 engineers.

## Software Engineer

WSO2

- **iii** January 2018 to July 2019
- Oclombo, Sri Lanka
- Delivered the Cellery observability basic features within 2 months for observing microservice composites, using Kubernetes, Istio, OpenTracing and Envoy.
- Headed the implementation of Cellery developer tools using Language Server Extensions and visualizations of Cells using D3.
- Developed Cellery Hub backed by a Docker Registry as storage and authentication of the CLI and portal using OpenID Connect (OIDC), collaborating with a team, within 1 month.
- Implemented the observability aspects of the WSO2 Serverless Platform using Prometheus and Jaeger on top of Kubernetes and OpenWhisk.

# **Skills**

- Programming languages Java, GoLang, Scala, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Frameworks and tools Express, React, TensorFlow, Numpy, Pandas, Azure Event Hub (Kafka), Testing (TestNG, Cypress), Kubernetes Operator Framework
- Storages Time-series Databases (Influx DB, Azure Data Explorer), Graph Databases (Orient DB), Data Lakes (Azure Data Lake), Relational Databases (MySQL, MsSQL), Redis
- **Deployment** Containerization (Kubernetes, Azure Kubernetes Service, Kustomize, Docker, AWS ECS), CI/CD (GitOps, Azure DevOps, GitHub Actions, GitLab), Monitoring (Prometheus, Jaeger, CloudWatch)
- API Protocols REST, GraphQL, gRPC
- Software Development Methodologies Agile, DevOps

## Certifications

Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning

Amii, University of Alberta iii September 2021

Build Basic Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)

Deep Learning Specialization

Certified Kubernetes Administrator

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

The Linux Foundation 

iii January 2020

### **Education**

### B.Sc. (Hons.) in Engineering (Computer Science and Engineering)

- Attained a GPA of 3.85 out of 4.20, obtaining a First Class.
- Placements in Dean's List in 6 out of 8 semesters at the University of Moratuwa.
- Awarded Global Finalist (Galactic Impact) in the NASA Space Apps Challenge 2017.
- Completed Google Summer of Code 2017.

# **Publications**

- "Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN) based Anomaly Detection in Industrial Software Systems" published in 2019 at Moratuwa Engineering Research Conference (MERCon)
- "Anomaly Detection in Industrial Software Systems Using Variational Autoencoders" published in 2017 at the Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Pattern Recognition Applications and Methods (ICPRAM)